<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[How To Adult: CS Edition]]></title><description><![CDATA[placeholder description please replace me.]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 18:31:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Finding Your First Internship]]></title><description><![CDATA[Confidence & Mindset: Dear freshmen, internships are not just for upperclassmen! Welcome to Georgia Tech’s campus. You may have already felt…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/internship/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/internship/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Confidence &amp;#x26; Mindset: &lt;strong&gt;Dear freshmen, internships are not just for upperclassmen!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Georgia Tech’s campus. You may have already felt this at the beginning of the semester, but August and September is always crunch time for attending info sessions and career fairs. Students use these platforms as a way to find an internship or job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a senior at Georgia Tech and veteran myself, I have heard many concerns from freshmen in particular about pursuing internships. The most common ones echo the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m a freshman. There’s so much time left. I don’t even know what I’m doing post-graduation. What would I even be doing with an internship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m a freshman, and have no experience. What’s the point when there are more qualified candidates?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I empathize with these sentiments and understand how intimidating it can be when your older friend has a beautiful and filled up resume while yours just has high school experience. However, using your doubts as a crutch will create a chicken-egg situation: you don’t have the experience to get an internship – you don’t have the internship to gain experience. Personally, I think the best thing to do for your career in college is to be proactive. Act and think later. Apply and think later. Attend those career sessions and think later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do things proactively, but not blindly. When you are speaking to company representatives, whether it be at the career fair or info sessions, the most effective way to present yourself is with intention. Employers love when a student can convey genuine interest for their companies. Even when you may not be the most technically qualified, that quality can take your candidacy a long way as knowing why you want to work for a company gives a longer lasting impression. So what is a way to research companies?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Georgia Tech’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://gatech-csm.symplicity.com/students/?signin_tab=0&quot;&gt;CareerBuzz website&lt;/a&gt; posts all of C2D2’s hosted info sessions and career fairs. Use the search filters to find companies that are open to hiring freshman candidates; filter to which industries you have general interest for; then research the companies’ own sites - I especially recommend pages like “Values” and “What We Do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you figure out which companies you are interested in, plan accordingly to fit career fair and info session dates onto your calendar. I recommend prioritizing which companies you are most interested in and know you have the greatest chance at. It is really easy to get overwhelmed trying to balance schoolwork and internship hunting, so a laser-focused priority list can alleviate that challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://career.gatech.edu/&quot;&gt;C2D2&lt;/a&gt; often also hosts mock interviews and resume workshops for you to brush up on your content. I remember signing up for mock interviews myself as a freshman - they all went horribly, but the practice was very helpful in helping me improve my confidence. You can sign-up for these professional development workshops on the CareerBuzz website as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, to give you a better sense of the internship landscape, here are the kinds of companies that usually come to recruit at Georgia Tech’s biggest career fair, All-Majors Career Fair: &lt;a href=&quot;https://career.gatech.edu/fall-2019-all-majors-career-fair&quot;&gt;https://career.gatech.edu/fall-2019-all-majors-career-fair&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over 350 companies came to recruit us in Fall 2019, so don’t doubt yourself and think you have no shot!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Resume&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;resume&lt;/strong&gt; is a document that lists your background, applicable skills, accomplishments, and any other pertinent information you would want your potential future employer to know. Other pertinent information could include things like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal technical projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any TA/tutoring positions you’ve held&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leadership positions in student organizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volunteer/social welfare contributions (Think Bits of Good or Girls who Code)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When describing these on your resume, be &lt;strong&gt;specific&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;concise&lt;/strong&gt;. You should aim to get all the information you want on your resume on one page. Anything longer than that will lose a recruiter’s attention or get auto-filtered out on an online application page. Do &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; put anything on your resume that you would feel unconfident talking about to a recruiter or during an interview. This will make you look like you don’t actually know what’s on your resume! Remember, the resume is only one part of securing an internship and is how you get your foot in the door of an employer. There’s still the interview portion, which we will cover later in the guide.
When designing your resume, you want to keep in mind that recruiters will be looking at hundreds of resumes, whether at the career fair or after being filtered if applying online. How do you stand out against the competition? Keep your resume formatting slightly different from the norm, but not too flashy. Afterall, your employer is more interested in your skills and talents than how well you can position things on a document. There is a phenomenon called the &lt;strong&gt;F-pattern reading&lt;/strong&gt; where people pay most attention when reading the first line of a paper, but as they continue to read, their attention gradually drops. Therefore, when deciding which sections should be higher up on your resume, put your most outstanding things that you want the recruiter to remember first then put your other sections. In every section, it is standard to list each subtopic chronologically, so it is easy for the recruiter to see growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Resume Example 1&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;  max-width: 590px;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/how-to-adult-prototype/static/e1729694a9ce7334eeb0b3dae6b31739/6f6fc/resume_example_1.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 166.2162162162162%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAhABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAGAABAAMBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAECAwX/xAAVAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAf/aAAwDAQACEAMQAAAB7iKQaitUGqVVyE3C/wD/xAAbEAADAAIDAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREhMQIQQf/aAAgBAQABBQIlFwxoouqIxYLR6tf/xAAUEQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAg/9oACAEDAQE/AV//xAAUEQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAg/9oACAECAQE/AV//xAAcEAABAwUAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAASAxEDJBUWH/2gAIAQEABj8C2SpcorM06S3/xAAcEAADAQEAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREhMUFRkWH/2gAIAQEAAT8hqTirC0YMgkm364XVj+lwfbXngltb9CYR23RKfHT0HsQ4H//aAAwDAQACAAMAAAAQNDhw98//xAAYEQACAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAESAhMf/aAAgBAwEBPxDRlQ//xAAXEQEAAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQASEx/9oACAECAQE/EMLJP//EAB8QAQACAgICAwAAAAAAAAAAAAEAESExQWGBoVFxsf/aAAgBAQABPxAbLYQ4mgV2V8RYZwB1bEFL2XjUwdC7tYiWee2UFXo3lTCmWDpRfqEHvO7myxEpcSlG6GIyruceX5NP3PQJ/9k=&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;Resume Example 1&quot;
        title=&quot;Resume Example 1&quot;
        src=&quot;/how-to-adult-prototype/static/e1729694a9ce7334eeb0b3dae6b31739/1c72d/resume_example_1.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/how-to-adult-prototype/static/e1729694a9ce7334eeb0b3dae6b31739/a80bd/resume_example_1.jpg 148w,
/how-to-adult-prototype/static/e1729694a9ce7334eeb0b3dae6b31739/1c91a/resume_example_1.jpg 295w,
/how-to-adult-prototype/static/e1729694a9ce7334eeb0b3dae6b31739/1c72d/resume_example_1.jpg 590w,
/how-to-adult-prototype/static/e1729694a9ce7334eeb0b3dae6b31739/6f6fc/resume_example_1.jpg 617w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Resume Example 2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;  max-width: 590px;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/how-to-adult-prototype/static/d18f08732c63d1f3e072ab38263f5743/4d731/resume_example_2.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 127.70270270270272%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAaABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwABAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAECBf/EABQBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAD/2gAMAwEAAhADEAAAAe5Q0DM3Cg//xAAUEAEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAw/9oACAEBAAEFAk//xAAUEQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAg/9oACAEDAQE/AR//xAAUEQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAg/9oACAECAQE/AR//xAAWEAADAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABITD/2gAIAQEABj8CLp//xAAbEAEBAAIDAQAAAAAAAAAAAAABABAhEUFRkf/aAAgBAQABPyEHlfEOsexF7GiLq6x//9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABBgDQz/xAAUEQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAg/9oACAEDAQE/EB//xAAUEQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAg/9oACAECAQE/EB//xAAaEAACAwEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREhMVEQ/9oACAEBAAE/ELINPMQVJlicipcmTBNVIIbGlT0at4WH/9k=&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;Resume Example 2&quot;
        title=&quot;Resume Example 2&quot;
        src=&quot;/how-to-adult-prototype/static/d18f08732c63d1f3e072ab38263f5743/1c72d/resume_example_2.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/how-to-adult-prototype/static/d18f08732c63d1f3e072ab38263f5743/a80bd/resume_example_2.jpg 148w,
/how-to-adult-prototype/static/d18f08732c63d1f3e072ab38263f5743/1c91a/resume_example_2.jpg 295w,
/how-to-adult-prototype/static/d18f08732c63d1f3e072ab38263f5743/1c72d/resume_example_2.jpg 590w,
/how-to-adult-prototype/static/d18f08732c63d1f3e072ab38263f5743/a8a14/resume_example_2.jpg 885w,
/how-to-adult-prototype/static/d18f08732c63d1f3e072ab38263f5743/fbd2c/resume_example_2.jpg 1180w,
/how-to-adult-prototype/static/d18f08732c63d1f3e072ab38263f5743/4d731/resume_example_2.jpg 1352w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above are two examples of resumes. The one on the left is very flashy and more oriented for a design position. As you can see there are not a lot of specific descriptors of the work the person has accomplished. However, the resume on the right is perfect for a technical role. It is easy to follow, has specific descriptions for many of his points, has minimal colors, and all fits on one page. There are many free resume templates you can find online, but stick to templates that have similar qualities of the resume on the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Tech, there are many resources that will help you hone your resume-making skills. Through C2D2, the CoC, and student orgs like Alpha Kappa Psi, you can attend resume workshops where experienced people can give you feedback on your resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Career Fair - in progress&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Behavioral Interviews&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behavioral interviews evaluate your personality, communication skills, and how well you bring your resume to life. Luckily, they are pretty standard across the board, and you should always prepare your answers ahead of time because you can always expect these questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell me about yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why do you want to work here?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is your favorite class in school?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell me about this class you took/internship you had/project you undertook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What interests you about (insert job type here)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did you ever have a time when you disagreed with someone you were working with and how did you overcome that?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell me about a time where you took on a leadership role&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are your preferred programming languages and why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While answering these questions, keep in mind that your interviewer is looking for how well you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hold a conversation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nervousness is understandable, but don’t let it cripple the conversation. Feel free to pause before you answer to collect your thoughts. Be polite and genial even if the interview isn’t going well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know your resume&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We all embellish a little bit on our resume. However, whatever you write is fair game for any questions about it. Err on the side of caution and don’t put that you are “proficient in C++” when you’ve only done a beginner’s tutorial, for example. The interviewer might be an expert in C++ and will know instantly if you’re bluffing from just a few questions, which will lose you a lot of points. If you are asked a question that you aren’t qualified to answer, don’t pretend you know and try to make something up. Instead, admit that you’re not sure, and give an educated guess.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communicate at a high level about what you accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When your interviewer asks you to explain what you did in a class/internship/project, keep it concise and use the STAR method: Situation, Task, Action, Result. Don’t spend too much time talking about the situation—a few sentences will suffice. The interviewer is interested in what actions you took and the results, not a whole backstory. Really highlight your contributions and role by using active voice, and don’t shy away from talking about the difficulties you faced (as long as you can explain how you overcame them).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can lead a team or take ownership of a project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This ties in with the previous point, but try to show that you can take initiative. Talk about an experience you had where you were responsible for a big part of the deliverables. Did you delegate any tasks to others? Make executive decisions that ultimately changed the direction of the project? Respond to any crises? If a project you did hits all these points, it’s a good one to bring up during the interview.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work with others and solve interpersonal conflicts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inevitably you’ll get a question on how you handled a disagreement with a colleague. Don’t talk about an experience that is too trivial—the interpersonal conflict should have stakes (for example, if a team member was uncommunicative, or you vehemently disagreed with them on how to implement something). The interviewer is trying to see whether you’d let a personal clash with someone else hinder the work you both had to work on (the answer is no, you wouldn’t let that happen).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researched the company you interviewed at&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should always always do research before you interview. Even though it doesn’t necessarily indicate whether you’d be a good employee, not knowing anything about the company will make you seem disinterested. Doing research will also give you insight on whether you’d like to work there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The interviewer might ask if you have any questions for them. Now’s a good time to ask about what he/she is working on, company culture, or anything else you’ve researched about them. This isn’t necessary to do well, but remember that you are also interviewing the company, so it’s in your best interest to get as much information from a person who works there as possible!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technical Interviews&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most companies will have at least one round of technical interviews, which test your knowledge of CS fundamentals. You may be asked to code, explain a technical concept, or design a system. Typically you will be interviewed by another engineer, or a technical manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A really great (and famous) resource to read is Cracking the Coding Interview by Gayle Laakmann. It’s a comprehensive guide and textbook rolled into one, with practice problems (and solutions) categorized by topic, explanations of CS concepts, and other helpful tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several types of questions you can get in a technical interview, but the most common is the coding question. This is the most common category. You will be given a problem description and some inputs, and you’ll have to write code that produces the solution in the correct format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Example 1: You are given a list of numbers, and a target number k. Write a function to determine whether or not there are two numbers in the list that add up to k.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, it won’t matter what language you write the solution in (pseudocode is fine in most cases). However, make sure to pick a language that you are familiar with. Even better if that language isn’t too verbose. You don’t want to waste time thinking about data types in Java or C, for example (which is why Python is a popular language people use for interviews). It’s more important that your code is readable and the logic is correct. Usually, interviewers will be lenient about minor syntax errors, so don’t stress too much about it. You could be asked to write the code by hand, or type it out on a computer. Some interviewers may require that the code be executable, in which case they will likely let you look up syntax online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tips on preparing:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be well versed in data structures and algorithms (taught in CS 1332).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common data structures used in interviews (not exhaustive): Hash map, hash set, array/list, stack, queue, tree, graph. For each data structure, know what the best use cases for them are, and the runtime complexity of adding/removing/finding elements in them and why. Know the terminology associated with each data structure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common algorithms used in interviews (not exhaustive): Breadth-first-search, depth-first-search, Dijkstra’s shortest path, topological sorting. Know the runtime complexity of each algorithm and why you would use it over others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Practice early, practice often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s one thing to know data structures and algorithms, but it’s another to use them to solve a problem. There are tons of practice problems out there. Great resources are Cracking the Coding Interview, LeetCode, or HackerRank. Recruiting season starts in September, so try to start practicing by the start of August. Do at least one problem a day, instead of cramming a bunch right before an interview.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try to simulate the real thing each time you do a practice problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pretend it’s an actual interview. Set a time limit for yourself, and don’t look at the answer until the end. Get rid of any distractions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk out loud, as if you’re explaining your thought process to someone. Better yet, get a group of friends together and mock-interview each other. This will reduce performance anxiety when it’s time for the real interview, because you’ll have strengthened your communication skills and your ability to think under pressure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GT TIP is a COC club that meets weekly and hosts technical interview workshops. It is a great resource for solving problems as a group and talking through solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you can’t get the solution in time, think critically about where your logic went wrong, or what you didn’t consider. What can you learn from this problem? What can you do in the future so this doesn’t happen again? Keep this in mind for the next problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;During the interview:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure you understand the problem.&lt;/strong&gt; If you don’t, &lt;strong&gt;ask questions&lt;/strong&gt;. Some interviewers will purposely leave out information to see if you’ll think to ask. It’s good to talk through a basic example as a sanity check. I’ve had some interviews where I assumed I knew the problem (I didn’t), and tried to solve the wrong thing for 20 whole minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask any relevant questions about the parameters of the problem. In example 1, you can ask what the output should look like, or if the list of numbers can contain negatives, or floats/doubles, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to think of the problem intuitively first, like a word problem. Some people get bogged down trying to first envision everything in terms of data structures, which gives you too much to think about at once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’re stuck, write out a naïve solution, then iteratively optimize it. Trying to write the most efficient solution right away is risky, because it takes a lot of time. Most of the time the interviewer would rather have a working solution written than a half-baked idea by the time the interview is over.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep describing your thought process.&lt;/strong&gt; Think of the interview like a conversation. The interviewer isn’t just evaluating your ability to find the solution. They’re also looking at how you think and whether you’re open to feedback and hints from them, which is hard to do if you don’t say anything. That being said, pausing to collect your thoughts every now and then is fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once you’ve got a solution down, it’s important to write test cases for your logic. Think of edge cases you haven’t covered. Think of how to handle invalid inputs. Think about the case where the input is huge, and if you’re being memory efficient. A lot of interviews may hinge on how good your test cases are, because that’s a huge part of writing good code in the real world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;After the interview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you solved the problem efficiently and accurately, congratulations! If not, don’t be discouraged. Hardly anyone does great on every interview. If there’s time at the end of the interview, ask your interviewer for feedback on how you did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Getting the Most Out of Your Internship&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations on getting that gig! Here’s how to make the most of those few months in a new workplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think carefully about your priorities for the internship. Internships are primarily for you to learn, and you’ll have more flexibility than regular employees, so use that to your advantage! Your manager will likely give you several project options. Consider your long term career goals, and pick the work that will get you there. If you’re not sure of long term goals, focus on projects that interest and challenge you. However, not every internship gives you freedom on what you work on, so be open-minded and put effort into whatever you’ve been assigned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set clear goals to keep organized and reduce stress. An internship can be daunting because there’s so much you need to learn and do in a short amount of time. Sit down with your supervisor/manager and set realistic goals for what you can accomplish during your time there. Break down those goals into weekly deliverables. Set daily tasks to help get you there. Some goals will end up taking longer (or shorter) time to achieve, so keep evaluating yourself and adjust your schedule as time goes on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write down what you work on each day. This may seem unnecessary, but don’t underestimate how quickly you can forget things a week later. Having a record of what you’ve done and learned will save you time, and is valuable after the internship when you’re interviewing again and need to explain what you did.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicate frequently and &lt;strong&gt;honestly&lt;/strong&gt; with your team, mentor, and manager. Don’t be scared of seeming incompetent - &lt;strong&gt;keeping quiet about problems you’re having will not help you or your team.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re confused or stuck on one thing for more than 30 minutes, ask for help. If you need more work to do, or if you feel like you’ve been given too much to do, inform your supervisor. If you have ideas, propose them to your team. Ask for feedback on how you’re doing. Being forthright about your progress will make you a dependable employee, and shows you can work with others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take initiative.&lt;/strong&gt; As an intern, no one expects you to know everything, but they do expect you to be able to find some answers on your own. There will probably be documentation and onboarding resources for new hires, so read those first for any preliminary questions. During the internship, you’ll probably need to consult people outside of your team, so make those appointments yourself. Be active during meetings, take ownership of what you’re working on, and don’t wait for someone to tell you what to do.
Network. Internships are the prime time to branch out, and the people you meet could become future friends, employers, coworkers, or mentors. Lunch breaks and company outings are a great way to talk to someone new. You can even ask someone to have coffee for 30 minutes in the break room! Don’t limit yourself to the people you work with—feel free to ping someone from a different team or organization. Most people are happy to talk about themselves and give advice to an intern. This can be daunting (and a little tiring if you’re an introvert), but stepping outside your comfort zone is a part of growing your career, and strengthening your networking skills will pay back in spades later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take notes on if you’d like to come back after graduating. Do you like the company culture? the work you’re doing? career advancement opportunities? career flexibility? Don’t forget to evaluate the city and state you’re interning in. Do you like the culture and vibe? How is the cost of living? What other career opportunities are there? Don’t forget an internship is also about you interviewing the company and surrounding area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Your First Full Time Job]]></title><description><![CDATA[Congratulations! You are in your last year at the Institute and wondering how to distinguish between your offers which would best suit you…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/full-time/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/full-time/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations! You are in your last year at the Institute and wondering how to distinguish between your offers which would best suit you and your goals. Keep reading to find out what you need to consider before signing an offer letter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What to Keep in Mind&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s the difference between an internship and a full-time career? Besides the obvious time commitment difference, you now need to be thinking of where you want to be in 5, 10, 15 years. The experience you gain from your first career out of college could be a building block to your goal of being a lead developer or it could have no impact on your journey to the top of the social pyramid. If you haven’t articulated your goals for the future, now is a good time to do so. These goals do not have to be set in stone, but having them in place will allow you to work on achieving them as you progress through your career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing that employers offer to full-time employees, but don’t offer interns as frequently are benefits. These benefits are typically a 401k match and various insurance plans. It’s important to look at these in your offer package as an offer with a lower salary could potentially give you more money in the long run through their benefits. Some companies may offer a sabbatical, which is an extended period of paid leave, but under the condition that you work at the company for an extended (&gt;5 years) time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving on to the next chapter of life is an exciting time, but it’s not something that you want to dive head-first into. Take some time to reflect and really evaluate what you want out of your career and how you can achieve that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Researching Your City&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have offers out of New York, San Francisco, Seattle, Boston, and so on, it can become a challenge to pick the location you vibe with the best when they all seem equally amazing. However, not all cities were made equal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest factor to consider when researching a city is how expensive rent is. A 1 bed/1 bath in Manhattan is going to be more expensive than a 1 bed/1 bath in Atlanta, so do your due diligence before signing a lease. A rule of thumb is that your monthly rent including all utilities should not exceed 30% of your monthly income before taxes. More often than not, living alone is more expensive than living with roommates, so if you know anyone else who also has offers in the same city you are looking at, you should reach out to them and see if they are interested in living together!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While apartment hunting, you should also keep in mind what your commute to work will look like? Does your city have spectacular and reliable public transportation? Or will it be a gamble to get to work every morning? Will you need to drive to work? Or can you walk a few blocks to get to the office? These are questions you should be asking yourself as the answer to a few of these questions will lead to more monthly expenses (vehicle, car insurance, monthly transport pass). In some states, car insurance is significantly more expensive than other states, so be sure to take note of possible rates you may have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important aspect to look into is crime around the areas you might live in. If rent is suddenly very cheap in a certain neighborhood of a city, there is probably a good reason why this is the case. It may not always be crime, but it is up to you to find the reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although not as critical, but just as necessary, is looking up nearby amenities and things to do in your city. If you like to go out to bars and clubs, but that scene doesn’t exist in a city you have an offer in, then you might not be as happy in that city compared to another one. Or if you enjoy hikes and nature and the beach, then a concrete jungle like Manhattan wouldn’t suit you. Just as it’s important to like what you’re doing at work, you need to enjoy what you’ll be doing outside of work for a healthy lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A helpful resource to compare how much a salary in one city equates to another is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nerdwallet.com/cost-of-living-calculator&quot;&gt;cost of living calculator&lt;/a&gt;, which can be found online for free. These calculators will give you an estimate of rent, transportation, food, entertainment, and healthcare costs in each city to provide you a good sense of the salary you would need to make to have the same quality of life in that city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This phase of the job hunt is either people’s favorite or their nightmare, but following these tips will make the selection process much less of a headache.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Finances]]></title><description><![CDATA[Intro: Congratulations! You’ve recently been hired for either an internship or a full-time position, probably as a software engineer. There…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/financial/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/financial/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Intro:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations! You’ve recently been hired for either an internship or a full-time position, probably as a software engineer. There is lots to unpack, especially on the financial side, as now you will have a steady flow of income that offers plenty of opportunity. In this section, we’ll be diving into what that entails, both for internships and full-time jobs. First, we’ll look at the ideal accounts required to build a healthy financial infrastructure. That will be followed by an approximate breakdown of your monthly income, followed by what specific things that money should funnel to. We’ll conclude with some common misconceptions people may have about finance as well as some additional resources that will enhance your understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Necessary Tools:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good set of accounts to have for anyone, interning or working full-time, is a set consisting of a checking account, at least one savings account, and an investment account. Paired with a few credit cards, this will allow for a healthy financial infrastructure. To clarify, a checking account is basically an account that stores your money for you to use and pay off certain things, it is essentially your virtual wallet. A savings account is an account that stores funds for short and long term goals, and usually is not delved into to deal with daily expenses. These accounts also usually have high interest rates associated with them in order for your money to grow faster. An investment account is usually a platform that invests your money into multiple or even just one account that will be either set aside for retirement and long term financial growth. Credit cards are cards that are used to make immediate purchases in daily life, which accrue an interest-free debt that is paid off at the end of each month, building credit (if cards are not paid off at the end of each month, the debt becomes interest heavy, hurting you!). These are a necessity to have in order to build credit for big purchases later in life, and if you do not own a credit card as a college student, it is highly recommended that you obtain one. For those without a steady or sufficient income, which is most students, secured credit cards are a good option to start building credit, as they do not require a credit score or good credit in order for you to obtain one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tools are all extremely important to building a healthy financial infrastructure that you can carry forward with you for the rest of your life. As an intern, certain practices discussed below will be different than as a full-time employee, but the tools above will provide the ability to have purchasing power and make efficient financial decisions at any point in your future. Even if all of these tools are unobtainable, don’t worry! Getting a good start on building a good financial infrastructure, no matter how small, is always better than doing nothing with the money you will be earning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really Great Checking Accounts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nerdwallet.com/best/banking/checking-accounts&quot;&gt;https://www.nerdwallet.com/best/banking/checking-accounts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal Favorite: Charles Schwab High Yield Investor Checking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really Great Savings Accounts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nerdwallet.com/best/banking/savings-accounts?trk=nw_gn2_4.0&quot;&gt;https://www.nerdwallet.com/best/banking/savings-accounts?trk=nw_gn2_4.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal Favorite: Capital One 360 Savings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best Credit Cards (choose the category most applicable to you, there is one for Students!):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nerdwallet.com/the-best-credit-cards?trk=nw_gn1_4.0&quot;&gt;https://www.nerdwallet.com/the-best-credit-cards?trk=nw_gn1_4.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For investment accounts, for the sake of this manual, we will be restricting information to discussing Roth IRAs and 401(k)s. There are a ton of investment options out there, and a good starting point is either or both of these accounts, depending on your employment type. The best practice for further investing is to do research on the many types of investment avenues available and to choose the one that best works for you and your lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you are aware of the ideal tools needed, go ahead and set up accounts in each category that you are comfortable with. If you are a full time employee, chances are that you will be offered some sort of company-contributed investment account. Definitely open an account and make sure you take advantage of the free money that the company is willing to invest in your future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have these tools ready for your use, the next step is to take a look at your internship or job income and break it down into healthy percentages of spending, saving, and investing, so that we can use these tools to funnel this income to the right places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Income Breakdown:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first good habit to get into before even thinking about what you will do with your money is calculating the tax rate that will be applied to your income, ensuring that you have a realistic idea of what money will actually be deposited into your account. A good tax calculator is linked below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://smartasset.com/taxes/income-taxes&quot;&gt;https://smartasset.com/taxes/income-taxes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can select your state, income, and tax filing status. If you are an intern, extrapolate your income to what it would be for a full year’s worth of salary, and then get the after tax value and reduce it back down to the number of weeks you will be interning. This number you get at the end of using the calculator is the money that will be deposited into your account over the course of time applicable. Divide this value by 12 to get your approximate monthly income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For both types of employment, relocation stipends and bonuses will also be taxed at the same percentages.
Now, the breakdown. There is a bunch of information out there about how your monthly income should be broken down, but a good rule of thumb to follow is explained in this graphic, with one important caveat:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;  max-width: 590px;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/how-to-adult-prototype/static/6b07219fafa936184c14bb6401c5d911/4a41d/budget.webp&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 66.89189189189189%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/webp;base64,UklGRn4AAABXRUJQVlA4IHIAAACwAwCdASoUAA0APtFUo0uoJKMhsAgBABoJZACw7CB0JiE3OfQ/8AD5tZR1qkEjn/Np8IOpqBSj1YHJ59MelHojx4gL3QJrTCj4sVA7995nWr8U6Lbj1fVfv2a8OZO2U/ghc+uTaYOwUOsO/u5ChBxAAAA=&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;Budgeting Rule Pie Chart&quot;
        title=&quot;Budgeting Rule Pie Chart&quot;
        src=&quot;/how-to-adult-prototype/static/6b07219fafa936184c14bb6401c5d911/5ca24/budget.webp&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/how-to-adult-prototype/static/6b07219fafa936184c14bb6401c5d911/cbe2e/budget.webp 148w,
/how-to-adult-prototype/static/6b07219fafa936184c14bb6401c5d911/3084c/budget.webp 295w,
/how-to-adult-prototype/static/6b07219fafa936184c14bb6401c5d911/5ca24/budget.webp 590w,
/how-to-adult-prototype/static/6b07219fafa936184c14bb6401c5d911/dad35/budget.webp 885w,
/how-to-adult-prototype/static/6b07219fafa936184c14bb6401c5d911/4a41d/budget.webp 950w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This graphic is mostly correct, with one missing detail. First, the savings category should be divided into two subcategories: savings goals and investments. Ideally, you want to put 10% of your income into retirement and other investments, while another 10% will go into short-term and long-term savings goals, such as tuition, a car, dining plans, etc. Other than that, the above pie chart paints a pretty accurate picture of how your income should be broken down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re an intern, chances are a good bit of the needs are already taken care of. Food may be provided at the office (as is the case with many software companies nowadays). You may be given a relocation stipend or be placed in corporate housing. If this is the case, and your needs such as groceries and utilities don’t make up 50% of your income, more power to you! You can take the rest of that percentage and divide it into the other categories as you see fit! Save more money, or spend more of it, especially if your needs category does not demand as much from your income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One important principle to keep in mind that will aid greatly in the use of your income is the concept of using your income on needs, saving/investing, and wants, in that order. This concept is known as “paying yourself first”, and is a common term that is applied to many things, such as working out in the morning so that you are done with it before you begin the day. Using your income in this order allows for the important parts of living a sustainable life to be taken care of, such as paying your rent on time and saving money for tuition. After that, once your essentials are taken care of and you have fulfilled the truly important necessities, you can then use whatever money that is left over on wants! This greatly mitigates the issue of overspending or not sticking to a “budget.” If you can first take care of the necessities, there does not have to be a hard cap on what you spend on fun things, as all of your essentials have already been taken care of. This leads to healthier and guilt-free spending on things you truly love, such as a new video game or an expensive dinner at that restaurant you’ve always wanted to try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breaking down your income as such organizes it as well as gives it purpose. This baseline will allow you to learn more about your own spending habits and changing needs. Feel free to tweak this plan as necessary, and if you are an intern returning to college, redistribute some of the percentages to work for yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step to discuss is where this money will specifically be funneled to. Yeah, you should be saving 10% of your money a month, but what exactly does that mean? Investing 10% of your income sounds fantastic, but which accounts are we putting this money into? It is important now to fully understand and interconnect your personal finance infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Personal Financial System:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you know what tools are needed in order to set up your financial infrastructure, as well as how you should ideally be splitting up your income, let us break down how to automate everything for your own convenience as well as where specifically the money should go. First, let’s start with the 401(k), one of the most important benefits your employer can offer you. If you are an intern, feel free to skip the next section, but keep in mind for when you do get full-time offers, 401(k) matches are an important benefit that most (if not all) companies offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;401(k):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 401(k) is a retirement account that your employer will most likely offer to you as part of your benefits. This is an account that you will not be able to open (without severe penalties) until you are 59 and ½ years old, but this is because this is a long-term retirement investment account that accrues money from your income &lt;em&gt;pre-taxes&lt;/em&gt;. That last part is really important, as this means that you can put a significant amount of money into this account to accrue value before it is taxed. This leads to about 25% more money you can contribute to your 401(k) over your lifetime, so take advantage of this. Chances are that your employer will offer you a match up to a certain percentage of your income, and if it is possible, you should try and max this out! This is because if a company is matching your contribution, this is literally free, pre-tax money that is going towards your retirement and long-term financial stability. Hence, to the best of your ability, try and max out your 401(k) at your company, and this will be a great step towards your financial future that you won’t even see in your monthly income from above. It is automatically deducted from your paycheck each month, which means that you are essentially “paying yourself first” in order to invest that money before you can use it. Try and max out your 401(k), and then move on to the other steps below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Paying off Needs/Fixed Costs:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless the world and life truly hates you, your rent and utilities every month will probably be a fixed cost. If you are an intern in corporate housing, this is already taken care of, but it is still a fixed amount that the company is paying to house you there. You want to make sure that the first thing you are doing when you receive your money each month is paying off these fixed costs and eliminating the headache of ever being behind on bills. Turn on auto-pay in your systems that demand a fixed cost each month, so that you know that you are paying off your bills immediately when your income comes in. This also gives you a more realistic picture of the money you have left to actually use for the rest of your expenses and desired spending, saving, and investing. Some fixed costs such as groceries can’t be set to “auto-pay”, but approximating the amount you need each month and making sure that remains in your account after the steps below should work well enough for needs that are not one-time payments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Credit Card Bills!:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing you want to do is to pay off all of your credit card “debt” accrued from the last month. The reason I put debt in quotes is because this is never real debt as long as you pay it off in full each month. Just to be crystal clear, if you want to avoid financial ruin, &lt;em&gt;pay off your credit card bills each month in FULL&lt;/em&gt;. Otherwise, credit card companies will ding you with a nasty little term called APR, which for all things that matter in this situation just means &lt;em&gt;a whole ton of interest&lt;/em&gt;. Any actual debt (note how it is not in quotes this time) that you carry over from a given month to the next will be hit with huge amounts of interest that will just add up over time. Pay it off in full and you don’t have to pay any interest on it, and you will build good credit, which will help for car loans, mortgages, and fun super adult stuff later on in life. Go to your credit card accounts and set up auto-pay each month in these from the checking account your income comes into (providing you are making enough for your spending), so that every month, your credit card will reach into your checking account and pay off your bill in full without you needing to worry. This will &lt;em&gt;further&lt;/em&gt; reduce the money you have to spend on stuff in the coming month, but don’t worry, that is because it was taking care of your spending from last month. If interning, once your internship is over, assuming you now will have a finite amount of money left for the near future, turning off auto-pay might actually be a good idea in order to make sure that you have enough money every month to pay your bills off. I personally did this in college in order to ensure I was never overdrafting from my checking account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Savings:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next place that your money should go to should be all of your savings goals, whichever those may be. If you have a short-term savings goal for a car in 5 years, or tuition in 3 months, set aside money for that each month, and set up auto-withdrawal from your savings account to your checking account, so that the money is being saved without any extra hassle on your end. Use your savings goals and actively save each month. Once this is done (approximately 10% of your monthly income), we have one more step before you literally can spend the rest of your money on whatever you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Investments:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember the other 10% of the savings bucket that I said needed to be accounted for? This is for investments, retirement accounts and other accounts. The first investment that should have occurred as a full-time employee should have been before you were even paid, in the form of your 401(k). After that, one good practice is to invest in a Roth IRA, &lt;em&gt;whether you are an intern or a full-time employee&lt;/em&gt;. You can open up a Roth IRA account in a lot of different places, with websites such as Vanguard or Fidelity being good options, but this is a very important account that should definitely be opened at a young age. A Roth Individual Retirement Account, or Roth IRA, is a retirement account that you deposit post-tax income into that will be invested and grown in order to be withdrawn at any age after 59 and a half (severe penalties if you withdraw before that age). The huge bonus of a Roth IRA is that when you withdraw money out of it once you retire, you will not be taxed on it, which means that you will keep all of the money that you have accrued on it. There is only a max contribution to the account each year of approximately $6,000, so regardless of if you are an intern or a full-time employee, opening one is in your best interests. Roth IRA’s are explained in this article below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/r/rothira.asp&quot;&gt;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/r/rothira.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides this main investment vehicle, you can also invest your money in stocks, bonds, and a bunch of avenues that may or may not net you money depending on how the market performs. A good safe option to invest your money is to invest money into low-cost index funds that grow with the economy and are low-risk for the long term. Fidelity, Vanguard, and a bunch of places have low-cost index funds that have fairly low and competitive fees, so check those out for investing your money further. Remember, due to inflation, if you save your money, it usually will lose value over time, so the best thing you can do with your money for the long-term is to invest it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Spending Time!:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have taken care of your present and future needs, the money you have left now is yours to spend. You don’t need to stick to a budget within the remaining money you have, because all of your important stuff is taken care of. This is the benefit of “paying yourself first.” You now can spend the money left in your account guilt-free, and on things you really want and desire, without worrying about penny pinching (given you have enough money). This allows for a better relationship with money and a sense of fulfillment when you are able to buy things that you have wanted because you have the leftover income to do so. Most of this spending will be done in the form of credit card spending, as spending on a credit card is a secure and efficient way to pay for things (as long as you are paying off your bills each month in full!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a basic summary of your financial system every month, with most of it being automated and hassle-free. This financial infrastructure will allow you to truly thrive while not worrying about fancy money terms that people will throw your way or get-rich-quick schemes. It is a boring but efficient and financially responsible system that will set you up for long-term success.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>